Finding Aid for the Robert Thomson Boxes
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Robert Thomson Boxes
multiple
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0700
4.05 linear_feet
- Holley, Mildred D. (Mississippi) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Zachariah Cox Letter, August 25, December 1794 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 2 Cox, R. P. Thompson (Box 1, Folder 3)
- II, 1700-1725 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- III, 1700-1725 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- IV, 1700-1725 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- V, 1700-1725 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- VI, 1700-1725 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- VII, 1700-1725 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- VIII, 1700-1725 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Outlines and Annunciations, 1725-1763 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- II 1725-1763 Outline- The Development of Market Machinery (Box 1, Folder 12)
- I. 1725-1763 C. The Gooch Tobacco Inspection System (Box 1, Folder 13)
- I 1725-1763 A. Commercial Duties and Legal Proceedings (Box 1, Folder 14)
- I 1725-1763 B. Comency Reform (Box 1, Folder 15)
- I 1725-1763 D. The Excise of 1733 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- I 1725-1763 E. Unofficial Schemes (Box 1, Folder 17)
- II 1725-1763 B. The Development of Market Machinery (Box 1, Folder 18)
- III 1725-1763 C. William Woodford (Box 1, Folder 19)
- II 1725-1763 D. John Norton and John Svelson (Box 1, Folder 20)
- II 1725-1763 E. The Bogles (Box 1, Folder 21)
- II 1725-1763 F. Andrew Meade (Box 1, Folder 22)
- II 1725-1763 G. Charles Stewart (Box 1, Folder 23)
- blank (Box 1, Folder 24)
- II 1725-1763 A. The Piedmont Expansion (Box 1, Folder 25)
- IVC (Box 1, Folder 26)
- American Association for State and Local History (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Market Auditions, 1749-1759 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- IV A (Box 1, Folder 29)
- (Box 1, Folder 30)
- IV D and IV E (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Statistical Efforts, 1725-1763 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Virginia Tobacco Prices, 1700-1750 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Rate of Exchange G.B.-Virginia, 1700-1775 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Regulation of Mercantile Activity (Box 1, Folder 35)
- The Morality of American History notes (Box 1, Folder 36)
- William and Mary College (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Letters to and from Dr. Roberts (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Unused Manuscript 1700-1725 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- I 1700-1725 Draft One (Box 1, Folder 40)
- II 1700-1725 Draft One (Box 1, Folder 41)
- III 1700-1725 Draft One (Box 1, Folder 42)
- IV 1700-1725 Draft One (Box 1, Folder 43)
- V 1700-1725 Draft One (Box 1, Folder 44)
- VI 1700-1725 Draft One (Box 1, Folder 45)
- VII 1700-1725 Draft One (Box 1, Folder 46)
- VIII 1700-1725 Draft One (Box 1, Folder 47)
- I 1725-1763 Final Drafts (Box 1, Folder 48)
- I 1725-1763 A-B First Draft (Box 1, Folder 49)
- II 1725-1763 William Woodford Draft One (Box 1, Folder 50)
- II 1725-1763 William Woodford Notes (Box 1, Folder 51)
- II 1725-1763 D. Svelson Notes (Box 1, Folder 52)
- II 1725-1763 E. Anderson Meade Notes (Box 1, Folder 53)
- II 1725-1763 F. Charles Stewart Notes and First Draft (Box 1, Folder 54)
- II 1725-1763 G. Bogles Notes (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Pattern of Mercantile Activity in Virginia, 1763-1775 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Notes on Note Taking: Sentence Writing (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Winterbotham (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Maryland Colleges in the Revolutionary Era (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Cokesburg College- Maryland (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Washington College- Maryland (Box 1, Folder 62)
- St. Johns College- Maryland (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Virginia Colleges: Liberty Hall (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Virginia Colleges: Hampden Sydney (Box 1, Folder 65)
- North Carolina Colleges during Revolutionary Era (Box 1, Folder 66)
- (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Letters to and from Robert Thomson (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, personal (Box 2, Folder 3)
- 350 Lecture IA- Location and Exercise of Power (Box 2, Folder 4)
- 350 Lecture IB- The Voice of the Citizen (Box 2, Folder 5)
- 350 Lecture IC- Schools and Colleges in Early America (Box 2, Folder 6)
- 350 Lecture ID- Educational Spokesmen (Box 2, Folder 7)
- 350 Lecture IIA- Carriers of Culture (Box 2, Folder 8)
- 350 Lecture IIB- Classical Forms in America (Box 2, Folder 9)
- 350 Lecture IIC- American Achievements in Art and Intellect (Box 2, Folder 10)
- 350 Lecture IID- Success and Failure in Institutions of Learning (Box 2, Folder 11)
- 350 Lecture IIIA- Measures of Nationalism (Box 2, Folder 12)
- 350 Lecture IIIB- Self-Conscious Nationalism (Box 2, Folder 13)
- 350 Lecture IIIC- A Mission for America (Box 2, Folder 14)
- 350 Lecture IIID- The School as an Instrument of National Purpose (Box 2, Folder 15)
- 350 Lecture IVA- Values (Box 2, Folder 16)
- 350 Lecture IVB- Native Forms (Box 2, Folder 17)
- 350 Lecture IVC- The Response of Schools (Box 2, Folder 18)
- History 500 Introduction (Box 2, Folder 19)
- 380 Reference Works (Box 2, Folder 20)
- 397- Writing and Style (Box 2, Folder 21)
- 397- Arendt: Understanding and Politics (Box 2, Folder 22)
- 397- Becker: Every Man His Own Historian (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Becker, “What Are Historical Facts?” (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Berlin, “Historical Inevitability” (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Butterfield- “Memorial Judgments in History” (Box 2, Folder 26)
- 397 Paul Conkin; Causation Revisited (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Degler: History Without a Beard (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Felix Gilbert on History (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Hempel- “The Function of General Laws in History” (Box 2, Folder 30)
- J.H. Hester, “Fernand Braudel” (Box 2, Folder 31)
- James Hooper, Oral History (Box 2, Folder 32)
- “The Historian and the Social Scientist” By H. Stewart Hughes (Box 1, Folder 33)
- 397 Huizinga: Historical Concepts; Tutilization (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Manual; “Use and Abuse of Psychology in History” (Box 2, Folder 45)
- 397 Morrison: Faith of a Historian (Box 2, Folder 46)
- 397 Namier: avenues of History (Box 2, Folder 47)
- 397 Popper: Critiques of Classical Theories of History (Box 2, Folder 48)
- 397 Strout: Causality (Box 2, Folder 49)
- 397 Susman: History and the American Intellectual: Uses of a Useable Past (Box 2, Folder 50)
- 397 Toynbee: Can We Know the Pattern of the Past (Box 2, Folder 51)
- 397 Wise: Implicit Irony in Perry Miller’s New England Mind (Box 2, Folder 52)
- J.H. Franklin “Century of Reconstruction History” (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Jonathan Wiener, “Class Structure and Economic Development in the Am. South, 1865-1955 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- 397 Zinn The Politics of History (Box 2, Folder 55)
- 397- Philosophy of History (Non-Current) (Box 2, Folder 56)
- W&M, 1760s (Box 2, Folder 57)
- W&M, 1770s (Box 2, Folder 58)
- William and Mary College, 1750-1800 (Box 2, Folder 59)
- Virginia Colleges of Revolutionary Era (Box 2, Folder 60)
- South Carolina colleges in the Revolutionary Era (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Tennessee Colleges, 1783-1800 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Kentucky College to 1800 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Political Theory (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Madison Pant and Awning Company (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Preliminary Examination for the Ph.D. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- 9-13-78 Book Review- PFE, George Peabody Col. THE FUTURE OF HISTORY.Vand.Univ.Symp (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Ammerman, David In the Common Cause book review rpt (Box 3, Folder 8)
- BOOK REVIEWS (HISTORY) ’78. The Southern Experience in the American Revolution. Jeffrey J. Crow & :arru Tise (Box 3, Folder 9)
- AERA- 1976 comments on papers (Box 3, Folder 10)
- COLONIAL GEORGIA- Review for the Journal of Southern History (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Review of Empire of Independence 1760-1776: A British-American Dialogue on American Revolution. Phil. Quart. ‘76 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Review of John H. Westerhoff, MCGUFFY AND HIS READERS: Piety, Morality and Education in 19thC. (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Review of THEIR MAJESTIES’ ROYALL COLLEDGE. The Virginia Gazette 11/76 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- A Time to Decide- The Making of Loyalists- talk to International Study Club November 75 by RPT (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Microcosm of Revolution- paper for sons of American Revolution, June 1976 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Notes on Signers of the Declaration of Independence (Box 3, Folder 17)
- The Loyalties in the American Revolution- RPT lecture at MTSU, 13 April 1976 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- 1978- Comments on Horne (Box 3, Folder 19)
- ASA (1968) Doing research on the Negro (Box 3, Folder 20)
- The Great Contours notes (Box 3, Folder 21)
- James Claypoole’s Letterbooks. Reviews (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Book Review: Affectionately Yours George Washington (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Review of: John Harrower diary (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Review: Colbourn The Lamp of Experience (Box 3, Folder 25)
- The Americans: The National Experience; and The Life of the Mind in America from the Reconstruction to the Civil War (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Review of Greenled. Ferry Hill Plantation Journal (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Book Review: Peter Magrath Yazoo: Law and Politics (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Malone Jefferson Review (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Review: Williamson Fitzhugh and His Chesapeake World (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Titus, Winston Churchill review (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Review of: The Emergence of a National Economy 1775-1815, by Nettels (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Lynd, Class Conflict Review (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Review of William Tatham (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Peabody Journal of Education 6/79. REVIEW, Donald R. Warren, editor. History, Education, and Public Policy (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Review- Lieutenant Lee of Beale Street (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Review: Crisis in the Classroom by Charles E. Silberman (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Review- Rouse, Parke, Jr. James Blair of Virginia (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Review of Correspondence of James K. Polk (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Review: George N. Rainsford Congress and Higher Education in the 19th century (Box 3, Folder 40)
- The Dawn’s Early Light Walter Word (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Review- Films- “Cause of Liberty” and “Impossible War” (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Illich’s Deschooling Society Review (Box 3, Folder 43)
- France and the Chesapeake by J. Price (Box 3, Folder 44)
- The Campus as Community (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Response- Field Teaching Essays (Box 3, Folder 46)
- A Task for The University (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Virginia Project (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Yearbook 1975- National Council for the Social Sciences (Box 3, Folder 49)
- English Ed. Writing, 18th century A-D (Box 3, Folder 50)
- English Ed. Writing, 18th century E-P (Box 3, Folder 51)
- English Ed. Writing, 18th century R-2 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- England, 1973 Trip to (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Impact of British on American Education, 1760-1800 (Box 3, Folder 54)
- History of American Education (On American Colleges) Winterbotham (Box 3, Folder 55)
- S.C. Trade Regulation 18th century (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Talk for Alexander’s course. Education 568 (Box 3, Folder 57)
- The Purpose of Teaching History (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Am. Lite and Lecture. Order and Disorder: Social Patterns in Colonial America (Box 3, Folder 59)
- History as a Contemporary Subject 1967 Private School Education (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Washington Birthday Speech (Box 3, Folder 61)
- Book of Knowledge. Colonial Life Article (Box 3, Folder 62)
- Some Thoughts on the Education of Curriculum Makers (Box 3, Folder 63)
- Lecture Education 545 B Social Foundations (Box 3, Folder 64)
- World Book: General (Box 3, Folder 65)
- OAH- 1970 Hemphill and Kay (Research and Writings) (Box 3, Folder 66)
- The Virginia Government and the Regulation of Commercial Activity (Box 3, Folder 67)
- Pattern of Mercantile Activity in Virginia (Box 3, Folder 68)
- Pattern of Mercantile Activity in Virginia (Box 3, Folder 69)
- St. George Tucker (Box 3, Folder 70)
- Book Outline (Box 3, Folder 71)
- I 1700-1725 (Box 3, Folder 72)
- History Course Grade Sheet, 1980-90 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- History 416, 400, 500, 529 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- History 502- Syllabus (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Jack Greene “Uneasy Condition- Preconditions of the American Revolution” (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Bernard Bailyn, “Central Themes of the American Revolution (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Daniel B. Smith, “The Study of the Family in Early America” (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Stephen S. Webb, extracts from book (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Bernard Bailyn, Voyages to the West 3-49, 243-245 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Morgan, Labor Problems at Jamestown (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Perry Miller, “Errand into the Wilderness” (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Darrett Rutman, Minor of Puritan Authority Reading II (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Jack Greene, Pursuit of Happiness Chapter 2, 8 pg. 28-54, 170-206 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- James Henretta, “Mentalite in Pre-Industrial America” (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Kulikoff, “Origins of Afro-American Society in Maryland and Virginia, 1700-1790 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- History 250- Readings. Bailyn: The Merchant Group at the End of the 17th Century (Box 4, Folder 15)
- History 250- Readings. Billington: The Reinterpretation of Early American History (Box 4, Folder 16)
- History 250- Readings. Campbell: English Emigration on the Eve of the American Revolution (Box 4, Folder 17)
- History 250- Readings. Laslett: John Locke, The Great Recoinage, and the Origins of the Board of Trade, 1695-1698 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- History 250- Readings. Lockridge: Land, Population and the Evolution of New England Society, 1630-1790 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- History 250- Readings. Namier: Why Men Went Into Parliament (Box 4, Folder 20)
- The Intellectual Golden Age in the Colonial Chesapeake Bay Country (Box 4, Folder 21)
- II. A. History of Education 201. Walzer, John “A Period of Ambivalence” (Box 4, Folder 22)
- II. B. History of Education 201. Tyack, David “Forming the National Character...” (Box 4, Folder 23)
- II. B. History of Education 201. Kaestle, Carl “Common Schools Before the Common School Revival...” (Box 4, Folder 24)
- II. B. History of Education 201. Sizer, Thoedore The Age of the Academies, 1-23 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- II. C. History of Education 201. Smith, Wilson Theories of Education in Early America, 1655-1819 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Education 307- Readings. Morgan: Ezra Stiles: The Education of a Yale Man, 1742-1746 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Education 307- Readings. Morison: The Founding of Harvard College (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Education 307: Readings Hiner: Adolescence in the 18th Century America (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Education 307- Readings Hiner: The Cry of Sodom Enquired into: Educational Analysis in 17th Century New England (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Education 307- Readings. Herbst: Yale Under Clapp (Box 4, Folder 31)
- History 250- Lecture. Liddle- Virtue and Liberty (Box 4, Folder 32)
- History 250- Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 33)
- History 250- Lecture. Great Britain and Her Colonies (Box 4, Folder 34)
- History 250- Lecture. The Colonial Cosmology (Box 4, Folder 35)
- History 250- Lecture. The American People, 1607-1763 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- History 201- Lecture. Learning to be Americans (Box 4, Folder 37)
- History 250- Lecture. Colonial Society (Box 4, Folder 38)
- History 250- Lecture. Colonial Economy (Box 4, Folder 39)
- History 250- Lecture. Economic Development (Box 4, Folder 40)
- History 250- Lecture. The Structure of Politics (Box 4, Folder 41)
- History 250- Lecture. Political Issues, 1750-1760s (Box 4, Folder 42)
- History 251- Lectures. The Coming of the American Revolution (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Ratification of the Articles of Confederation (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Loyalists (Box 4, Folder 45)
- History 251- Lecture. Emergence of Political Traditions, 1789-1805 (Box 4, Folder 46)
- History 251- Lecture. The Birth of the American Levathon (Box 4, Folder 47)
- History 251- Lecture. American Culture and Society, 1790-1828 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- The Crossing of the Sea (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Education 307- Lecture Notes and Readings, 1800-1850 (Box 4, Folder 50)
- History of American Education- Early 19th century (Box 4, Folder 51)
- History 251- Lecture. Sectional Economics in the Age of Nationalism (Box 4, Folder 52)
- History 251- Lecture. Political Processes (Box 4, Folder 53)
- History 251- Lecture. Jacksonian Politics (Box 4, Folder 54)
- History 251- Readings (Box 4, Folder 55)
- Statistics (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Mackencher memorial 1737 and newspaper controversy, 1738 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Darnall affair (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Excise Scheme, 1733 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Gooch Inspection Act, 1730 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Tobacco Inspection Act, 1738 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Tobacco Inspection Acts (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Virginia Trade with Great Britain, 1725 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Rough Chronologies and Notes. Virginia Legislation, 1700-1725 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Merchant’s Practices 1700-1725. Rough Notes and Data (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Report to Colonial Williamsburg. Thomson (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Sources (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Glossary of 18th Century Virginia Terms (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Critiques of major works on Virginia economic history (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Tobacco prices, 1770-1775. Taken from notes (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Virginia exports by district, 1772-1773 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Population Growth (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Governors of Virginia; Chronology (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Population, 1700 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Virginia Trade with Great Britain (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Slave Trade, 1700-1735 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Political Science 404 Lecture/Notes (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Lectures Political Science 404 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- History 150 Lecture Notes (Box 6, Folder 3)
- History 151 Lecture Notes (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Susskind, Jacob (Ph.D.) (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Program of Studies, 1971-1975 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Program of Studies, 1966-1970 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Program of Studies, 1961-1965 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Program of Studies, 1958-1962 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Christ Church Vestry (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Kathy Conlon (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Mashari, Ebrahim (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Sam Otaigbe (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Area Paper. Jack L. Seymour. Box 1003 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Jack L. Seymour: Dissertation Proposal (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Seymour, Jack (Ph.D.) (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Program of Studies, 1976-1980 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Buchannan, David J. PEY GR Summer, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Carrell, William D. (Ph.D.) (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Chilton, John F. (Ph.D.) (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Casteel, James Doyle (Ph.D.) (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Debolt, Tom (Ph.D.) (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Hiner, Ray (Ph.D.) (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Johnson, Tony Wayne (Ph.D.) (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Lambkin, John (Ph.D.) (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Myers, Charles B. (Ph.D.) (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Schneider, Don (Ph.D.) (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Correspondence-Personal, 1970-76 (Box 6, Folder 29)
- Episcopal Diocese Commission on Schools (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Friends of the Library, Board of Directories ‘79 (Box 6, Folder 31)
- Correspondence- Personal, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 32)
- GRE Guidelines to Use (Box 6, Folder 33)
- Institute of Public History (Box 6, Folder 34)
- Public History Project (Box 6, Folder 35)
- Peabody College- A Selected Bibliography (Box 6, Folder 36)
- Questions Submitted by RPT. Doctorate (Box 6, Folder 37)
- Questions Submitted by RPT. Masters (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Recommendations (Box 6, Folder 39)
- Reprints (Box 6, Folder 40)
- Travel (Box 6, Folder 41)
- Correspondence, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 42)
- Correspondence, 1968 (Fall) (Box 6, Folder 43)
- Correspondence, 1968 (Spring) (Box 6, Folder 44)
- Correspondence, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 45)
- Correspondence, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 46)
- Correspondence, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 47)
- Correspondence, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 48)
- Correspondence, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 49)
- Correspondence, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 50)
- Correspondence, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 51)
- Correspondence, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 52)
- Correspondence, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- General Education Materials (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Job Correspondence Material (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Termination (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Review of So. Ed. (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Demographic Implications for Peabody’s Enrollment and Curriculum Planning RPT (Box 7, Folder 9)